westchestergov.com 2015-12-08

# Disclaimer

Thank you for visiting Westchester County’s Web site. We recognize that those who use our Web site must be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit westchestergov.com. This policy describes our privacy practices regarding information collected from users of this Web site and our applications. It describes what information is collected and how that information is used. Because this privacy policy only applies to this Web site and our applications, you should examine the privacy policy of any Web site, including other governmental Web sites, that you may access via links from this Web site.

For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning an individual which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that person. Westchester County does not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail or by initiating an online transaction, including, but not limited to, registering for a Civil Service exam or e-filing documents.

**Information collected automatically when you visit this Web site**   
When visiting this Web site, Westchester County automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit:

i. The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used, but not the e-mail address. The Internet Protocol Address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer;

ii. The type of browser and operating system you used;

iii. The date and time you visited this site;

iv. The web pages or services you accessed at this site;

v. The web site you visited prior to coming to this web site;

vi. The web site you visit as you leave this web site; and

vii. If you downloaded a form, the form that was downloaded.

None of the foregoing information is deemed to constitute personal information. The information that is collected automatically is used to improve this Web site's content and to help us understand how users are interacting with the Web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis, to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users, and to improve the utility of the material available on the Web site. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and Westchester County is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from the Web site for commercial marketing purposes.

**Cookies**   
Cookies are simple text files stored on your web browser to provide a means of distinguishing among users of this Web site. The use of cookies is a standard practice among Internet Web sites. To better serve you, we use "session cookies" to enhance or customize your visit to this Web site. Session cookies can be created automatically on the device you use to access this Web site. These session cookies do not contain personal information and do not compromise your privacy or security. We may use the cookie feature to store a randomly generated identifying tag on the device you use to access this Web site. A session cookie is erased during operation of your browser or when your browser is closed. The software and hardware you use to access the Web site allows you to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies. Refusing or deleting these cookies may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of this Web site.

**Information collected when you e-mail this Web site or initiate an online transaction**   
During your visit to this Web site you may send an e-mail to one or more Westchester County department. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message including text characters, audio, video, and graphic information formats will be collected. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this Web site, or to forward your message to another governmental entity for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes.

Westchester County does not knowingly collect personal information from children or create profiles of children through this Web site. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access. Westchester County strongly encourages parents and teachers to be involved in children’s Internet activities and to provide guidance whenever children are asked to provide personal information online.

During your visit to this Web site you may initiate a transaction such as submission of an application for a Civil Service exam or the filing of a court record. The information, including personal information, volunteered by you in initiating the transaction is used to operate various Westchester County departmental programs, which include the provision of goods, services, and information. The information collected by our departments may be disclosed for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in connection with which the information was submitted.

**E-mail lists**  
During your visit to this Web site, you may wish to join one or more e-mail lists to receive important news or public alerts on a variety of subjects. We do not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease the addresses on our lists to anyone. In addition, our list servers are configured so they do not divulge the e-mail addresses of our list subscribers. Members of any list may un-subscribe automatically by following the instructions provided within emails sent to a list.

**Information and choice**   
As noted above, Westchester County does not collect any personal information about you during your visit to this Web site unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail or initiating an online transaction. You may choose not to send us an e-mail or submit data via an online transaction. While your choice not to contact us or submit documents to Westchester County may limit your ability to receive specific services through this Web site, it will not prevent you from requesting services from Westchester County by other means and should not have an impact on your ability to take advantage of other features of the Web site, including browsing or downloading certain publicly available information except in instances when using an online application is required by law.

**Disclosure of information collected through this Web site**   
Westchester County will only collect personal information through this Web site or disclose personal information collected through this Web site if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal information, except as otherwise provided below. The voluntary disclosure of personal information to Westchester County by the user, whether solicited or unsolicited, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by Westchester County for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to Westchester County, as was reasonably ascertainable from the nature and terms of the disclosure.

However, Westchester County may collect or disclose personal information without user consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of Westchester County, or necessary for Westchester County to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by county, state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.

Westchester County may disclose personal information to law enforcement authorities to enforce Westchester County’s rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to Westchester County’s information technology assets.

**Retention of information collected through this Web site**   
The information collected through this Web site is retained by Westchester County in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of New York State Law. Information, including personal information, that you submit in an e-mail or when you initiate an online transaction such as submission of an application for a civil service exam or the filing of a court record is retained in accordance with the records retention and disposition schedule established for the records of the program unit to which you submitted the information.

**Confidentiality and integrity of personal information collected through this Web site**   
Westchester County is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through this Web site against unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Consequently, Westchester County limits county employee access to personal information collected through this Web site to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information are required to follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information.

In addition, Westchester County has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of this Web site as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of the Web site for all users, Westchester County employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage this Web site.

**Disclaimer**   
Information provided on this Web site is intended to allow the public an alternative form of access to public information. While all attempts are made to provide accurate, current, and reliable information, Westchester County recognizes the possibility of human and/or mechanical error. Therefore, Westchester County makes no representations as to the accuracy, completeness, timeliness or suitability of the information provided by this web site, and denies any expressed and implied warranty as to the same.

**Links to other sites**   
This Web site contains links to other sites. Westchester County is not responsible for the privacy practices of such Web sites. A link does not constitute an endorsement of the content, viewpoint or accuracy of such Web sites.
